Frederick D. Thomas, Jr.

C: (919) 525-0548 | <u>SuperCodingNinja@outlook.com</u> 21006 130th Avenue CT E, Graham, WA 98338

Summary

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer & Emerging Engineer. I design and develop New experiences, which makes people's lives simple. I'm also a war **Veteran** (Marines), from minority demographics, with <u>24+years</u> of various work experiences, which has taught me to build valuable relationships: I love winning people. I have <u>savvy computer knowledge</u> (self-taught, and various courses leading to <u>Certification</u>). I have worked in high demand and stressful environments. I look for <u>problems to solve</u> and I focus on <u>responsive design</u>. I observe new trends, and my inference stems from winning system, "**G. A. M. E.**: **G**ather the Facts, **A**nalyze them, **M**ake a plan; and **E**xecute it, Triumphally- that's how you win a Game!"- F. Thomas, Sr. I'm a <u>critical thinker</u>. Let's change our world, together; and make it better for one another.

Computer Skills

Technologies: TypeScript (TS and TSX), Adobe Creative Cloud, Bootstrap4, Content Delivery Network, express, Heroku, MySQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Mongoose, MongoJS, HTML5, CSS3, SAAS, SCSS, AngularJS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON Parsing Libraries, ReactJS, Markdown, chart.js, git, webpack, Postman, Travis CI, bcrypt, JWT Authentication, React and React Router, Mutler; and expanding.

Version Control: GitHub, GitLab

Team Apps: ClickUp, Zoom, Slack, Google Teams

IDE: Visual Studio Code, Atom, and Popular Online IDE such as Repl and CodePen **Technical Interests**: Microsoft .NET, Python, scikit-learn, IBM Cloud (<u>IBM Watson A. I.</u>)

OS: MAC, Windows, Android, IOS, Google Chrome, Ubuntu **Browsers**: Edge, Chrome, Explorer, Mozilla, Opera, Netscape

Office Apps: Microsoft Office Suites, Google Docs, Apache OpenOffice, Kingsoft Office

Customer Relationship Management Software (CRM): Oracle, Salesforce

Other Software Experience: Angus, TrakTik, TrakShift, TekWave, Lenel, Avigilon, SilverTrac, C-Cure, Milestone, Genetec, OnSSI, Cisco Applications (Security Officer)

Recent Work Experience

Protective Services (Private Sector) and Security Industry (Various Affiliates)

Independent Contractor, Protective Specialist, Special Response Officer (SRO), 09/2014-Feb/2021 2020 Washington State

- Entrusted to train fellow Officers, Management, Client, and Clientele
- Highly Proficient with Negotiation, De-escalation Tactics, and Security Systems (including Badge Modification and Access Control, Alarm Monitoring, Electronic Remote Access Control, and CCTV)
- Dispatched Security for multiple High Valued Clients
- Awarded: EMPLOYEE OF THE MONTH, Candidate for Employee of The Year, Internal Operations Awards, and Bonuses and Wage Increase
- Provided Services for Major Online Retailer, GSOC Operations and Badge Access Control
- Proficient with Security Systems, access control, alarm monitoring, and CCTV
- M.O.A.B. Trained, CPR and AED Certified, and Held Unarmed and Armed Licenses

Certified in Over Fifty (50) Personal Extra Curricular Training Courses, Achieved Master Security
Officer Level 5 (Highest Level, Approximately Sixty (60) Academy Courses), Certified in Over Thirty
(30) Client Specific Training Courses

Xerox Services-Affiliated Computer Services

Customer Service Representative/Tier 1Technical Support, 04/2014-10/2014 Washington State

- Provided first-level contact and problem resolution for customers with hardware, software and applications problems
- Resolved user-reported problems using available tools and following procedures and policies for handling the support cases
- Performed to-the-level of all expected benchmarks (response times, issue resolutions, etc.)
- Provided accurate and timely logging of problems and resolution for problems in the specified database(s)
- Acted as a liaison between customers and external support staff to assure accurate problem interpretation, while working in a fast-paced environment
- Maintained communications with customers during the problem resolution process

United States Marine Corps

Non-Commissioned Officer in Charge/Acting Platoon Sergeant, Active Duty 2001-2005 Classified

- Planned and conducted the routine and day-to-day unit operations, within the policies established, by my senior officers: Logistics and Embarkation, Communications, Security, and several Command/Operation Billets
- Acted as a liaison between subordinate troop, peers, and superior officers
- Served On and Helped Pioneered Shock-Trauma Platoons (STP) and Forward Resuscitative Surgery System (Awarded The Navy Achievement Medal)

Education

University of Washington Coding Bootcamp Seattle, WA

Full-Stack Web Developer, Code Bootcamp – September 2020- April 2021 Expecting Certificate the beginning of April 2021

Code Fellows Seattle, WA

Full-Stack Web Developer, Code Bootcamp – 2016-2017

Completed Code Courses 101, 102; and 201 (scored 82.96 while working Full-Time, passed 301 Course Entrance Exam)

Self-Taught Coder Graham, WA

Full-Stack Web Developer and Engineer, Self-Taught – 2014-<u>Present</u> LinkedIn, Udemy, FreeCodeBootcamp, various Free Microsoft Courses

New Testament Christian Seminary *Graham, WA*

Licensed Minister, Certificate of Religion -2011

DeVry University [former campus] Federal Way, WA

Sophomore, Majored in Network Communications Management -2009 to 2011

Community Involvement

New Testament Christian Churches of America, Inc. (2002-Present): Personal Evangelism Outreach, Music Program, Active Minister License (2011-Present)